

YAWAR ALI

House No. 395-D Adam road, near old race course ground Karachi Cantt, Karachi Pakistan.

Cell: 0301-2996602 Email: yawarali 786@hotmail.com LinkedIn: myawarali

PROJECTS

Final Year Project

Design, analysis and solution optimization of an oil well using ALS - Artificial Lift System In technical collaboration with PPL and Weatherford.

HVAC System

Heating and cooling load calculation, chiller selection, diffuser selection, duct sizing and P&I diagram of a three floor building.

Design of a Car

Designed shell and chassis of a car for Shell Eco Marathon project and a car for handicapped people using SolidWorks.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- MS Office
- Solid Works
- HAP
- PTC Creo
- MATLAB
- ANSYS

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Problem Solving Ability
- Result Oriented
- Team Management
- Stress Management

MEMBERSHIP AND AFFILIATIONS

- Pakistan Engineering Council
- ASME Student Member
- IMechE Affiliate
- WWF Pakistan Member
- Youth Parliament Member

PERSONAL INTEREST

- Wanderlust
- Sports
- Current Affairs
- Social Work
- Gardening

OBJECTIVE

Mechanical Engineering graduate having elementary experience of machine shop management. Through my experience I have honed my managerial and technical skills to be more resourceful for my future employer. I intend to get employment in an organization that can offer attractive remuneration, learning environment & long-term career prospective in my respective field.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Trainee Engineer | Bolan Castings Limited (Hub, Pakistan) Machine Shop

April 2018 - Present

- Organizing and managing production schedules.
- Liaising with material management, quality assurance.
- Organizing the repair and routine maintenance of production equipment.
- Labour management.

Marketing & Sales Executive | Brandsmen (Karachi, Pakistan)

October 2017 - April 2018

- Accomplishing marketing and sales target.
- Planning developing, implementing and evaluating; advertising, merchandising and trade promotions of clients.
- Contributing marketing and sales information and recommendations to strategic plan
 review.
- Staff and labour management.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering | DHA Suffa University 2013 – 2017

CGPA: 3.53 - 3rd position holder

Majors: Project Management, Production Management, Maintenance Engineering, HVAC, Computer Aided Design and Manufacturing.

Higher Secondary School Certificate | Bahria College Karachi 2010-2012

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Merit Scholarships | DHA Suffa University 2013-2017

Graduated as 3rd position holder of batch. Getting merit scholarship in 5 out of 8 semesters.

Founder and President | ASME DSU Student Section 2013 - 2015

Organized different workshops, seminars and events as president of the student chapter of American Society for Mechanical Engineers.

International Award for Young People | HRH Duke of Edinburgh 2012

My efforts for community services were recognized by The International award for young people given by HRH Duke of Edinburgh.